JORGE CONTRERAS-LORETO

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Contact

- jorgeacl.me
- **4** +1 (206) 376-1103
- **♥** Greater Seattle Area
- in linkedin.com/in/jorgeacl
- cont12

Summary

Self-taught programmer. Coding is a skill with unlimited potential and it represents an opportunity for me to both develop myself further and create meaningful work that can help make other's lives better. I have a business background and have experience both managing teams and leading projects. I am a firm believer that teams who enjoy working together communicate more efficiently and do better quality work.

Education

Instituto Tecnológico y de Estudios Superiores de Monterrey (ITESM) Bachelors International Business 2012

Instituto Tecnológico y de Estudios Superiores de Monterrey (ITESM) Certificate Finance 2016

Projects

Devs4Good

Platform through which web developers can give back to the community by bringing non-profit visions to life.

AidUp!

Platform through which users can share planned volunteering activities for others to join.

Chantli Mare

Web page for a Mexican Boutique Hotel created with React.js

Skills

TECHNICAL SKILLS: CSS, Ruby, JavaScript, JQuery, AJAX, Github, Rspec, SQL, Sinatra, Active Record, Ruby on Rails, React.js

LANGUAGES: Spanish 100%, English 100%, French 50%

Experience

Dev Bootcamp

Student Mar 2017 to Aug 2017 · Seattle

Full-time, immersive full-stack web development program focused on:

- Object-oriented design (Ruby, JavaScript).
- Fundamentals of building interactive websites (HTML, CSS, AJAX, JQuery).
- HTML request/response frameworks and APIs (Ruby on Rails, Sinatra).
- Working with databases (SQL, PostgreSQL, Active Record).
- Client-side programming, scalable design patterns, deployment techniques.
- Test-driven development (RSpec).
- · Agile collaboration and workflows, engineering empathy and relationships in work teams.

Marmoletti

Internal Control Manager

Feb 2015 to May 2017 · Guadalajara, Jalisco, Mexico

- Analysis of internal procedures of 5 major departments to identify flaws and create a Procedures Manual framework and monthly preventive audits.
- Creation of inventory distribution plan to supply the company's 7 branches with the optimal mix of products.
- Creation of annual, monthly and weekly sales forecasts, monthly and weekly expense allocation and budget planning.
- Conciliation of registered sales versus actual income for 8 branch offices and creation of Income Statement for horizontal, vertical and financial ratios analysis.
- Compilation of statistical information and report creation for strategical decision making.

Project Manager Oct 2014 to Feb 2015

- Project Manager for implementation of new ERP Program (Stone Profit Systems).
- Compilation and organization of all the company's information (clients, suppliers, payment terms, inventories, financial balances, etc.) in preparation for data migration and coordination with U.S. ERP suppliers for the company's data migration.
- Creation of new procedures within the company that could work with the ERP's capabilities.
- Creation of ERP's written user guide and training program for >40 users.

PwC

International Trade & VAT Consultant

Jun 2012 to Jun 2014 · Guadalajara, Jalisco, Mex

- Trade procedure audits for various companies in different industries to ascertain compliance with international trade laws and regulations.
- Analysis and review of companies' international trade operations structure to identify opportunities, reduce risks, establish best practices.
- Presentation of improvement proposals for companies' import department structure and International trade operations.
- Organization and implementation of monthly committees and periodical seminars focused on Mexican international trade law.